<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>
        Transcription of
        <biblStruct>
                  <monogr>
                     <title level="j">
                        <seg type="main">Bruno's Weekly</seg>
                     </title>
                     <imprint>
                        <biblScope unit="vol">1</biblScope>
                        <biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
                        <date when="1915-07-12">Monday July 12, MCMXV</date>
                     </imprint>
                  </monogr>
               </biblStruct>
            </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Princeton University</publisher>
            <idno type="bmtnid">bmtnaaq_1915-07-12_01</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title level="s">The Blue Mountain Project</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblStruct>
               <monogr>
                  <title level="j">
                     <seg type="main">Bruno's Weekly</seg>
                     <seg type="sub">Edited by Guido Bruno in his Garret on Washington Square</seg>
                  </title>
                  <imprint>
                     <biblScope unit="vol">1</biblScope>
                     <biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
                     <date when="1915-07-12"/>
                  </imprint>
               </monogr>
               <relatedItem type="host" target="bmtnaaq"/>
               <relatedItem type="constituent" xml:id="c001">
                  <biblStruct>
                     <analytic>
                        <title level="a">
                           <seg type="main">The proof that liberty is the divine ideal of man, is that she is</seg>
                        </title>
                        <respStmt>
                           <persName>Alphonse de Lamartine</persName>
                           <resp>cre</resp>
                        </respStmt>
                        <textLang mainLang="eng"/>
                     </analytic>
                     <monogr>
                        <imprint>
                           <classCode scheme="CCS">TextContent</classCode>
                           <biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
                        </imprint>
                     </monogr>
                  </biblStruct>
               </relatedItem>
               <relatedItem type="constituent" xml:id="c002">
                  <biblStruct>
                     <analytic>
                        <title level="a">
                           <seg type="nonSort">Les</seg>
                           <seg type="main">Confidences: Being the Confessions of a Self-made American</seg>
                        </title>
                        <textLang mainLang="eng"/>
                     </analytic>
                     <monogr>
                        <imprint>
                           <classCode scheme="CCS">TextContent</classCode>
                           <biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8">1-8</biblScope>
                        </imprint>
                     </monogr>
                  </biblStruct>
               </relatedItem>
            </biblStruct>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
<profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <classCode scheme="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/">300312349</classCode>        
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="Magazine">
            <div type="Issue">
               <div type="PublicationInfo">
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P1_TB00001">
                        <lb facs="P1_TL00001"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P1_TB00002">
                        <lb facs="P1_TL00002"/>Edited by Guido Bruno in his Garret on Washington Square</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P1_TB00003">
                        <lb facs="P1_TL00003"/>MONDAY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P1_TB00004">
                        <lb facs="P1_TL00004"/>JULY 12, MCMXV</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P1_TB00005">
                        <lb facs="P1_TL00005"/>Vol. I</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P1_TB00010">
                        <lb facs="P1_TL00036"/>Copyright 19 /5 by Guldo Bruno</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P2_TB00002">
                        <lb facs="P2_TL00002"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P3_TB00001">
                        <lb facs="P3_TL00001"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P4_TB00002">
                        <lb facs="P4_TL00002"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P5_TB00001">
                        <lb facs="P5_TL00001"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P6_TB00002">
                        <lb facs="P6_TL00002"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P7_TB00001">
                        <lb facs="P7_TL00001"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
                  <div type="GenericPubInfo">
                     <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                         xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                         facs="P8_TB00002">
                        <lb facs="P8_TL00002"/>BRUNO'S WEEKLY</ab>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="EditorialContent">
                  <div type="TextContent" corresp="c001">
                     <div type="Byline">
                        <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                            xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                            facs="P1_TB00007">
                           <lb facs="P1_TL00011"/>Alphonse de Lamartine</ab>
                     </div>
                     <div type="Copy">
                        <div type="BodyContent">
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P1_TB00006">
                                    <lb facs="P1_TL00006"/>The proof that liberty is the divine ideal of man, is that she is<lb facs="P1_TL00007"/>ihe first dream of youth, and that she does not fade from our<lb facs="P1_TL00008"/>soul until our heart is withered and our mind either debased or<lb facs="P1_TL00009"/>discouraged. There is not a soul twenty years old that is not<lb facs="P1_TL00010"/>republican. There is not a decayed heart that is not servile.</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                        </div>
                     </div>
                  </div>
                  <div type="TextContent" corresp="c002">
                     <div type="Head">
                        <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                            xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                            facs="P1_TB00008">
                           <lb facs="P1_TL00012"/>Les Confidences: Being the Confessions<lb facs="P1_TL00013"/>of a Self-made American</ab>
                     </div>
                     <div type="Copy">
                        <div type="BodyContent">
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P1_TB00009">
                                    <lb facs="P1_TL00014"/>IN the solitude of my garret have I thought about all this busi<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P1_TL00015"/>ness that is setting aflame with barbaric rage one world and<lb facs="P1_TL00016"/>creating uneasiness, constraining personal liberty and sowing<lb facs="P1_TL00017"/>the seeds of hatred among brothers in the other.<lb facs="P1_TL00018"/>And because I am an American citizen, and because I thank<lb facs="P1_TL00019"/>the belligerent countries for some of the best and most essential<lb facs="P1_TL00020"/>things of my life, I feel that I must voice these thoughts of my<lb facs="P1_TL00021"/>solitude and tell them to you, who were born and raised in<lb facs="P1_TL00022"/>America, and who might better understand after this, and to<lb facs="P1_TL00023"/>you who are citizens as I am by your own choice, but who<lb facs="P1_TL00024"/>perhaps had never time or inclination or the intuition to think<lb facs="P1_TL00025"/>about it all.<lb facs="P1_TL00026"/>Well do I remember the dav on which I resolved to make<lb facs="P1_TL00027"/>•0<lb facs="P1_TL00028"/>this country my own. It was nearly a year after my arrival in<lb facs="P1_TL00029"/>the United States. I had just finished reading the writings of<lb facs="P1_TL00030"/>Abraham Lincoln. I wanted to be a citizen of the country this<lb facs="P1_TL00031"/>man had lived and worked and finally died for.<lb facs="P1_TL00032"/>Hero worship! But how I would wish to be as young<lb facs="P1_TL00033"/>again! My ideals carried me with uncurtaiied wings high above<lb facs="P1_TL00034"/>all material matters—above disappointments not spared to any<lb facs="P1_TL00035"/>of us, and all those little disasters which are part of our lives.</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P2_TB00003">
                                    <lb facs="P2_TL00003"/>I had admired Alexander the Great; Napoleon had beer, my<lb facs="P2_TL00004"/>ideal for years. Power, strength, determination of will, mak<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P2_TL00005"/>ing other people do what he thought was best for them,—that<lb facs="P2_TL00006"/>had impressed me. To read the lives of these men, to study<lb facs="P2_TL00007"/>their methods and their actions brought me elevation and ga e<lb facs="P2_TL00008"/>me ambition.<lb facs="P2_TL00009"/>Being the product of a monarchistic system, raised in ari<lb facs="P2_TL00010"/>atmosphere of discipline, of castes and of traditions, I was<lb facs="P2_TL00011"/>be deeply impressed with the European Republic—with Franc-<lb facs="P2_TL00012"/>Liberte! Egalite! Fraternite!<lb facs="P2_TL00013"/>I searched for it in France and I could not find it. Maybe I<lb facs="P2_TL00014"/>was too young in those days; maybe I was not able to translate<lb facs="P2_TL00015"/>the ideal into existing conditions. Maybe I was considering life<lb facs="P2_TL00016"/>as it was more than as it had been planned to be.<lb facs="P2_TL00017"/>And I became a cynic; I lost my belief in real things. I<lb facs="P2_TL00018"/>wanted to live my own life outside of the community of men<lb facs="P2_TL00019"/>whom I did not trust, who seemed to me egotists, sailing under<lb facs="P2_TL00020"/>a false flag of idealistic endeavors. Too deeply rooted in me<lb facs="P2_TL00021"/>was my early education of respect for laws and regulations to<lb facs="P2_TL00022"/>do anything desperate, or to join the groups of the dissatisfied,<lb facs="P2_TL00023"/>of men who call themselves betterers of humanity, and whom<lb facs="P2_TL00024"/>humanity calls outlaws, parasites or reformers.<lb facs="P2_TL00025"/>And so I decided to live my own life in the "New World,'<lb facs="P2_TL00026"/>to think as I wanted to think, to believe what I wished to be<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P2_TL00027"/>lieve, not to know anything of government, not to be a part of<lb facs="P2_TL00028"/>a system. As work which should furnish me with the necessi<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P2_TL00029"/>ties of life, I chose hard menial labor. Work that anybody<lb facs="P2_TL00030"/>could do who had strength and physical ability, where there were<lb facs="P2_TL00031"/>no questions asked, no contracts made. I came in the morning<lb facs="P2_TL00032"/>and received my pay in the evening, if I wished to. If I didn't<lb facs="P2_TL00033"/>like the work, I could quit it. And while I was working to earn<lb facs="P2_TL00034"/>my room and board, my thoughts were my own. And never in<lb facs="P2_TL00035"/>my life did I feel freer than in those days in which I had ex<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P2_TL00036"/>changed my pen for a shovel.<lb facs="P2_TL00037"/>I frequented the libraries. In my work clothes I strolled<lb facs="P2_TL00038"/>in, asked for any book I wished to read. Can you recollect the<lb facs="P2_TL00039"/>red tape you have to go through if you ask for a book in the</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P3_TB00003">
                                    <lb facs="P3_TL00003"/>?urary in France, in Germany or in Italy? Not the big trage<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P3_TL00004"/>iit'S of life make for unhappiness, but the small, little annoyances<lb facs="P3_TL00005"/>spoil for us the pleasure of enjoying this world.<lb facs="P3_TL00006"/>J "I do the very best I know how, the very best I can, and<lb facs="P3_TL00007"/>mean to keep doing so 'til the end. If the end brings me out<lb facs="P3_TL00008"/>alp right, what is said against me won't amount to anything."<lb facs="P3_TL00009"/>I These are the words of Lincoln, uttered at a time when he<lb facs="P3_TL00010"/>■<lb facs="P3_TL00011"/>seemed entangled in a labyrinth of political complications. I<lb facs="P3_TL00012"/>nbad his life, I read everything I could find about him, about his<lb facs="P3_TL00013"/>countemporaries, and now after more than fifty years have<lb facs="P3_TL00014"/>elapsed since his tragic death, these words of his have proven<lb facs="P3_TL00015"/>t!'ue. He had been far above the criticism of his time; he had<lb facs="P3_TL00016"/>feen only one goal for his life, one path leading to this goal, and<lb facs="P3_TL00017"/>lie walked this path. He saw the ambushes; he anticipated the<lb facs="P3_TL00018"/>stones which would be hurled at him from behind, but he walked<lb facs="P3_TL00019"/>pn. He had one life and the only vocation of his was to live<lb facs="P3_TL00020"/>that life of his. His words—and his words were his life—<lb facs="P3_TL00021"/>showed me what this country meant to the world, what America<lb facs="P3_TL00022"/>had been and was for all nations, for all races.<lb facs="P3_TL00023"/>AND so I stood there before the clerk in a western city and<lb facs="P3_TL00024"/>desired to make my application for American citizenship.<lb facs="P3_TL00025"/>It was a formality of a couple of minutes. I glanced over the<lb facs="P3_TL00026"/>slip of paper he handed me. There it stood, black on white,<lb facs="P3_TL00027"/>glaring into my face, that I had to renounce the sovereign, the<lb facs="P3_TL00028"/>prince whose subject I then was.<lb facs="P3_TL00029"/>There are moments in the life of every human being when<lb facs="P3_TL00030"/>his brain works with a hurrifying alacrity. Thoughts, memories,<lb facs="P3_TL00031"/>vivid pictures of scenes that have left an everlasting impression<lb facs="P3_TL00032"/>shoot through the brain in terrifying quick succession. They<lb facs="P3_TL00033"/>follow one the other, covering as long a stretch of years as our<lb facs="P3_TL00034"/>conscious and unconscious memory goes back in our lives. It<lb facs="P3_TL00035"/>happened there to me. In the clerk's office while I was look<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P3_TL00036"/>ing at the disinterested face of the man who wanted me to raise<lb facs="P3_TL00037"/>my hand and repeat the oath and to be done with me. I saw<lb facs="P3_TL00038"/>myself as a young boy singing patriotic songs. I saw myself<lb facs="P3_TL00039"/>as a youth in uniform with unsheathed sword swearing an oath</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P4_TB00003">
                                    <lb facs="P4_TL00003"/>of allegiance to my king. How terrible that oath was! "Dur<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P4_TL00004"/>ing day and night," the oath reads, "in water and on land, (in<lb facs="P4_TL00005"/>peace and in war, will I follow his leadership, will I be loyal to<lb facs="P4_TL00006"/>him. Even against my father and my brothers will Ibe loyal<lb facs="P4_TL00007"/>to him."<lb facs="P4_TL00008"/>i<lb facs="P4_TL00009"/>And then I thought how I had been educated at his ex<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P4_TL00010"/>pense, being a beneficiary of a stipendium, how I had to than&gt;k<lb facs="P4_TL00011"/>him indirectly for my college and for my university education.<lb facs="P4_TL00012"/>And I thought of my father and of his father and of all of m;y<lb facs="P4_TL00013"/>ancestors, and I thought of my brothers who wore his coat ancj<lb facs="P4_TL00014"/>spent their lives in his service, and all this I thought in less<lb facs="P4_TL00015"/>than a minute, and I told the clerk that I would come back ori<lb facs="P4_TL00016"/>another day to sign my declaration of intention.<lb facs="P4_TL00017"/>I do not take myself more seriously than is necessary in<lb facs="P4_TL00018"/>order to be taken seriously by others. I always hated cere<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P4_TL00019"/>monies and climaxes of any kind, but on that day I felt some<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P4_TL00020"/>thing that I never had felt before. I felt I was giving birth to<lb facs="P4_TL00021"/>I<lb facs="P4_TL00022"/>myself. Instead of doing as I had done so often in questions!<lb facs="P4_TL00023"/>of importance, to wait until the moment presented itself and then<lb facs="P4_TL00024"/>act, I decided to have it out with myself.<lb facs="P4_TL00025"/>A man who wanted to live his own life, a man who could<lb facs="P4_TL00026"/>not give himself up to the narrowness of his surroundings, who<lb facs="P4_TL00027"/>was willing to give up everything, to sacrifice the fruits which<lb facs="P4_TL00028"/>long years of study and a professional training would have<lb facs="P4_TL00029"/>brought him, because he could not accept certain traditions and<lb facs="P4_TL00030"/>convictions—an iron ring around his head and an untrans<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P4_TL00031"/>gressable wall enclosing his ambitions—must have the ability to<lb facs="P4_TL00032"/>forget, to erase out of his mind completely what has been. Or<lb facs="P4_TL00033"/>the thoughts what could have been will come and torture him<lb facs="P4_TL00034"/>and make him regret and kill him.<lb facs="P4_TL00035"/>For years I had not thought. I felt a stranger in my own<lb facs="P4_TL00036"/>past, as I was sitting there in my dark little hall room thinking<lb facs="P4_TL00037"/>of my allegiance to my king whom I had to abrogate in order to<lb facs="P4_TL00038"/>become an American citizen.<lb facs="P4_TL00039"/>A TEACHER paid by him or by the government whose earthly<lb facs="P4_TL00040"/>impersonation he is, had taught me to read and to write.<lb facs="P4_TL00041"/>His schools gave me a military training and the military disci-</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P5_TB00003">
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00003"/>pline taught me that great lesson millions of our brother citizens<lb facs="P5_TL00004"/>seem never to have learned: To keep my mouth shut and obey<lb facs="P5_TL00005"/>orders.<lb facs="P5_TL00006"/>That was about all that I wanted to say thanks for to the<lb facs="P5_TL00007"/>country of my birth. I came to this conclusion after I had<lb facs="P5_TL00008"/>guided my thoughts through twenty-three years of my life. I<lb facs="P5_TL00009"/>surprised myself at musings of sympathy and of pity for many<lb facs="P5_TL00010"/>ot those who had been associates of my youth. While my coun<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00011"/>try gave me my education, I had to go to other countries for<lb facs="P5_TL00012"/>food to sustain my real self. I had to go to the philosophers of<lb facs="P5_TL00013"/>Germany, I had to go to the poets and artists of France, I had<lb facs="P5_TL00014"/>to go to the singers and musicians of Italy and to the dramatists<lb facs="P5_TL00015"/>of England for all those essential things that make my real life<lb facs="P5_TL00016"/>worth living. And then I recollected those months that I had<lb facs="P5_TL00017"/>spent in this new country of my choice. 1 remembered how<lb facs="P5_TL00018"/>nobody asked me questions, how nobody put obstacles in my<lb facs="P5_TL00019"/>way, how everybody seemed to take me for granted, looking into<lb facs="P5_TL00020"/>my eyes and sizing me up as the man I seemed to be.<lb facs="P5_TL00021"/>I summed up the impressions I had received during my stay<lb facs="P5_TL00022"/>in the United States. The streets of New York loomed up in<lb facs="P5_TL00023"/>my mind. I saw the Italian selling his Italian wares, the Ger<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00024"/>man the products of his country, the French the specialties of<lb facs="P5_TL00025"/>France, I saw Norwegian and Swedish skippers, I saw the ghetto<lb facs="P5_TL00026"/>with its typical life, I saw the Armenian with his carpets and I<lb facs="P5_TL00027"/>saw the Greek and the Turk and the Spaniard; in the Metropoli<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00028"/>tan Opera House there was German and Italian and French<lb facs="P5_TL00029"/>opera. The book stores were laden with the Anglicised litera<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00030"/>ture of the world. The museums bore witness of everything<lb facs="P5_TL00031"/>beautiful that had ever been created in any part of the world at<lb facs="P5_TL00032"/>any age. The most remarkable, the most useful, the most bene<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00033"/>ficial things of the universe were brought here, put to the dis<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00034"/>posal of, annexed and assimilated by the American. And the<lb facs="P5_TL00035"/>American himself had come once from one of these countries<lb facs="P5_TL00036"/>and had taken possession of all that he found and had given in<lb facs="P5_TL00037"/>exchange all that he had.<lb facs="P5_TL00038"/>He had come as I did.<lb facs="P5_TL00039"/>And I realised that to be American means to be cosmopoli<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P5_TL00040"/>tan.</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P6_TB00003">
                                    <lb facs="P6_TL00003"/>To be cosmopolitan means to be big, to be high above small<lb facs="P6_TL00004"/>hatred and petty jealousy and ill-directed ambition. It means to<lb facs="P6_TL00005"/>be a brother to mankind, a fellow-builder of this world.<lb facs="P6_TL00006"/>While I had felt the laws of every country that I had lived<lb facs="P6_TL00007"/>in constraining personal liberty of the individual, I saw them<lb facs="P6_TL00008"/>here apparently made for the protection and for the benefit of the<lb facs="P6_TL00009"/>citizen . I was young in those days!<lb facs="P6_TL00010"/>A PESSIMIST, he who has given up hope, turns easily into an<lb facs="P6_TL00011"/>enthusiast. Over there in my own country by not com<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P6_TL00012"/>plying with the average requirements of that particular class to<lb facs="P6_TL00013"/>whom I belonged by birth and among whom to live would have<lb facs="P6_TL00014"/>been my fate I hardly could have done anything with my life.<lb facs="P6_TL00015"/>I always would have been the apostate.<lb facs="P6_TL00016"/>Here all paths seemed to me open to any goal I might set for<lb facs="P6_TL00017"/>myself. I had just finished reading the writings of Lincoln<lb facs="P6_TL00018"/>and I felt that everybody could do things in this country. Peo<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P6_TL00019"/>ple would consider the merit of things done and would not ask,<lb facs="P6_TL00020"/>"Who is he—why did he do it?"<lb facs="P6_TL00021"/>I felt they would give me a chance.<lb facs="P6_TL00022"/>And how I wanted a chance!<lb facs="P6_TL00023"/>And then I thought what I would do with my life. I de<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P6_TL00024"/>cided to stay here for good, to make America my own country.<lb facs="P6_TL00025"/>And then and. there I bade farewell to the past, to my king and<lb facs="P6_TL00026"/>to my country.<lb facs="P6_TL00027"/>I became an enthusiast again. I wanted to give everything<lb facs="P6_TL00028"/>so as to be worthy to receive. I went up to that clerk's office<lb facs="P6_TL00029"/>on one of the next days and made tabula rasa. I swore off an<lb facs="P6_TL00030"/>allegiance which had become sham without flesh and without<lb facs="P6_TL00031"/>blood.<lb facs="P6_TL00032"/>VEARS came and years passed. I found that there was a vast<lb facs="P6_TL00033"/>difference between a Lincoln and the lives of Americans I<lb facs="P6_TL00034"/>was confronted with every day. I found that not everything is<lb facs="P6_TL00035"/>gold that shines. The enthusiasm cleared away like clouds—<lb facs="P6_TL00036"/>beautiful clouds, dreamy, rose-colored clouds, but never did I<lb facs="P6_TL00037"/>miss the silver lining.</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P7_TB00003">
                                    <lb facs="P7_TL00003"/>I know America from East to West and from North to<lb facs="P7_TL00004"/>South. I know its people, those wonderful people who till the<lb facs="P7_TL00005"/>soil, who raise cattle, who mine hundreds of yards beneath the<lb facs="P7_TL00006"/>surface; I know the people of the city who work and scheme<lb facs="P7_TL00007"/>and labor and slave. I know the rich who had more at the day<lb facs="P7_TL00008"/>of their birth than an average human being could ever earn in<lb facs="P7_TL00009"/>three-score years: I know those wonderful geniuses who mould<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P7_TL00010"/>ed their lives to their own desire, and I know the unfortunates<lb facs="P7_TL00011"/>who await on park benches the dawn of a new day of misery.<lb facs="P7_TL00012"/>I KNOW this country, with the beauty of Italy, the romance<lb facs="P7_TL00013"/>of Spain and of Switzerland, with the marshes and pastures<lb facs="P7_TL00014"/>of France and of Germany. And the people are big-minded<lb facs="P7_TL00015"/>and big-hearted; they are dreamers but builders, lovers of the<lb facs="P7_TL00016"/>beautiful but utilizers of beauty: everything that is fit to survive<lb facs="P7_TL00017"/>—everything that was created to last forever is a part of this<lb facs="P7_TL00018"/>United States. It is the cosmopolis as a whole and in its small<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P7_TL00019"/>est village.<lb facs="P7_TL00020"/>JNEVITABLY will there arise in every community which,<lb facs="P7_TL00021"/>through individual vote, expresses its individualism by the<lb facs="P7_TL00022"/>election of one leader, the occasion when he will have to act as<lb facs="P7_TL00023"/>the supreme executive. The President of the United States is<lb facs="P7_TL00024"/>the leader of every citizen. At a time of crisis he has to shoul<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P7_TL00025"/>der the gravest responsibility that ever burdened a human be<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P7_TL00026"/>ing. He has to think, he has to come to conclusions which mean<lb facs="P7_TL00027"/>life and death to thousands, to millions of those who look up to<lb facs="P7_TL00028"/>him with trust and with confidence.<lb facs="P7_TL00029"/>Would you call an American a loyal American citizen who<lb facs="P7_TL00030"/>interferes with his President while he is meditating the gravest<lb facs="P7_TL00031"/>problem perhaps ever to be solved by a President of the United<lb facs="P7_TL00032"/>States? Can he be called an American citizen who forgets his<lb facs="P7_TL00033"/>oath of allegiance to this country—be it acquired by birth or by<lb facs="P7_TL00034"/>his own free choice—and tries by means that can be called either<lb facs="P7_TL00035"/>"making use of his right of free speech" or open vulgar treason<lb facs="P7_TL00036"/>to interfere with the highest executive who alone can act, who<lb facs="P7_TL00037"/>alone must act and who alone will be responsible to posterity for<lb facs="P7_TL00038"/>the occurrences during his administration?</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                           <div type="Paragraph">
                              <div type="Text">
                                 <ab xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
                                     xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
                                     facs="P8_TB00003">
                                    <lb facs="P8_TL00003"/>Be it good or be it bad, be it wise or be it hasty, be it peace<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P8_TL00004"/>bringing, or involving us in a disastrous war, like one man we<lb facs="P8_TL00005"/>must stand back of him whom we have chosen to be our Presi<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P8_TL00006"/>dent—in the time of crisis our leader.<lb facs="P8_TL00007"/>the descendants of all nations of the world, feel today<lb facs="P8_TL00008"/>better than ever that to be American means to be cosmo<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P8_TL00009"/>politan. And while we rage against this nation or that nation<lb facs="P8_TL00010"/>we forget above all the most vital thing in life: good taste. We,<lb facs="P8_TL00011"/>who are brother citizens of the descendants of all nations, can<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P8_TL00012"/>not, now or ever in the future, speak ill of any nation without<lb facs="P8_TL00013"/>hurting the feelings of a descendant of that nation who breathes<lb facs="P8_TL00014"/>our American air and who may be sitting at our table.<lb facs="P8_TL00015"/>The decision of our President must be final with us.<lb facs="P8_TL00016"/>America does not know military conscription, but everybody is<lb facs="P8_TL00017"/>expected to be a soldier in time of need. A bad soldier is he<lb facs="P8_TL00018"/>who discusses the possible actions of his leader ahead of their<lb facs="P8_TL00019"/>event. And a failure in life is he who complains and mumbles<lb facs="P8_TL00020"/>and talks even after he realizes that his choice of leader was<lb facs="P8_TL00021"/>not the wisest. The individual ceases to have an own will and<lb facs="P8_TL00022"/>an own opinion if he is bound by his oath and by the honor of<lb facs="P8_TL00023"/>his manhod to follow one leader. A coward is he who resigns<lb facs="P8_TL00024"/>in the last second, who is not willing to sacrifice his individual<lb facs="P8_TL00025"/>convictions and even conscience for his country.<lb facs="P8_TL00026"/>There are no hyphenated citizens. There are citizens and no<lb facs="P8_TL00027"/>citizens.<lb facs="P8_TL00028"/>OYPOCRISY it is to hoist the American flag and at the same<lb facs="P8_TL00029"/>time incite hatred against nations. Just as cosmopolitan as<lb facs="P8_TL00030"/>the United States are, just as cosmopolitan as its people is—<lb facs="P8_TL00031"/>and therefore truly American, the American flag is the highest and<lb facs="P8_TL00032"/>supermost symbol of the universal love of the kindred of men.<lb facs="P8_TL00033"/>Abolished is the distinction of races. Black be the body of a<lb facs="P8_TL00034"/>man or white, as long as he has a white soul he is one of us.<lb facs="P8_TL00035"/>And white are the stripes, next to the red, red as the blood that<lb facs="P8_TL00036"/>pulsates in the veins of everything that is alive, of everything<lb facs="P8_TL00037"/>that is created and might find its way to the hospitable shores of<lb facs="P8_TL00038"/>the land of liberty. And the dome of blue arches above all of<lb facs="P8_TL00039"/>us in all parts of both hemispheres and the stars are there, those<lb facs="P8_TL00040"/>kind, benevolent eyes of eternity which follow us wherever we<lb facs="P8_TL00041"/>go, that bring peace to our hearts and hope and beauty, if we<lb facs="P8_TL00042"/>only lift our eyes to find them.<lb facs="P8_TL00043"/>And because every one of the belligerent countries gave me<lb facs="P8_TL00044"/>an essential part of my life, and because I lived in all of them,<lb facs="P8_TL00045"/>and because I claimed the United States as my own, and be<pc type="endhypen" pre="false">-</pc>
                                    <lb facs="P8_TL00046"/>cause I am looking to our President as to my leader and to the<lb facs="P8_TL00047"/>United States as my just claimant, I feel that to be an American<lb facs="P8_TL00048"/>means to be cosmopolitan.</ab>
                              </div>
                           </div>
                        </div>
                     </div>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
